Matthew J. Morana

mattmorana7@gmail.com | 774-249-0654 | in/matthewmorana

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Highly-driven, passionate Lehigh University MBA candidate and former student-athlete. Experience in developing client relationships, financial analysis, and modeling with a Big Four global consulting firm. Excellence in leadership, team dynamics, and stakeholder management.

SAP S/4 HANA | MS Excel | Python | R | MS PowerPoint | Salesforce | Analysis-for-Office (AO) | MS Project | Visio | MS Power BI

EDUCATION

M.B.A., (Business Analytics), Lehigh University, Bethlehem, PA

August 2022

GPA: 3.9, Beta Gamma Sigma

B.S., Business and Economics, Lehigh University, Bethlehem, PA

May 2019

Major: Supply Chain Management; Minors: Business Information Systems, International Relations

GPA: 3.5, Dean's List, Lean Six Sigma Yellow Belt

WORK EXPERIENCE

Deloitte (New York, NY)

Engagement Financial Advisor Analyst & Consultant

July 2019 - June 2021

- Ranked top 5% nationally among Deloitte Analysts based on performance feedback from Partners and Senior Managers
- Monitored financials for 15 premier consulting projects simultaneously, ranging from \$200K to \$35M
- Meetings with Partners and Senior Managers re: weekly and biweekly cadences
- Improved efficiency/productivity by 25% by developing/leading new training regimens for on-boarded U.S. and India Analysts
- Built pricing model for client's largest-ever consulting project \$35M with 250+ staff members spanning 14 months
- Created 50+ pricing models on upcoming consulting engagements to support Partners and Senior Managers
- Administered \$60M+ in fee and expense invoices with 0% error rate
- Delegated workload to reduce project costs by collaborating with India team members
- Performed monthly out-of-pocket consulting team expense audits
- Reduced cycle time in collections by managing weekly billings for \$30M client account
- · Supported global projects and subcontractor partners, managing complex contractual arrangements/logistics

Hanover Insurance Group (Worcester, MA)

Personal Lines Product Intern

June 2018 – August 2018

- Succeeded in team competition re: RFP to identify/pitch a non-profit investment
- Analyzed a sample size of high-profile customers, presented findings and recommendations to VP
- Recovered, formatted, and posted 150+ missing policies to document library

Lehigh University Capstone: P.C. Rossin College of Engineering and Applied Science (Bethlehem, PA)

Voltu Motor, Inc. – Technology company with focus on renewable resources (www.voltumotor.com)

January 2018 – May 2018

- Researched electric vehicle industry, reporting findings to client
- As team member developed a regenerative braking system with ABS and traction control
- Delivered weekly briefings detailing individual and team contributions
- Generated bill of materials, projected cash flow, and developed tornado sensitivity diagram for new braking system

LEADERSHIP

Deloitte Mentorship Program (College Recruiting Platform)

October 2020 – June 2021

- Dedicated several hours/month to select college sophomores providing insight into Deloitte's operations
- Assessed presentation modules and delivered feedback to enhance mentorship program

Deloitte Collaborative Initiative

October 2020 – June 2021

- Enhanced culture, morale, and team bonding by organizing a monthly "game event" for NY office
- Led breakout groups, receiving positive reviews for cultivating office unity during the pandemic

Lehigh University Men's Soccer (Division I)

August 2015 - November 2018

- Selected as team captain as junior and senior
- Recipient of Scholar Athlete Award; Honor Roll, Patriot League
- Dedicated 25 hours per week to sport during Fall/Spring season

Lehigh Athletics Leadership Academy - Student Athlete Mentor

August 2015 – May 2018

Mentored freshmen student-athletes to align with Lehigh community

Professional Soccer Team (New England Revolution Academy)

July 2012 – August 2017

- Captain, under-16/under-18-year-old teams in high school; Member, under-23 team during college summer
- Invited to participate in 7 U.S. National Team training centers used to recruit for the Men's National Team